Hello, my name's Alex Price. And you are Selma Ahmed, right?
Yes.
Thank you. Can you spell your family name for me please?
A-H-M-E-D.
Thank you. Where are you from?
London.
Thank you.
Exam begins. LanguageCert ESOL International Speaking and Listening Preliminary Level 12 May.
Now, part one. I'm going to ask you some questions about yourself.
What do you do in the morning?
Sorry?
I get up. I drink orange juice.
OK. When do you watch TV?
Er, evening.
What weather do you like?
Weather.
Yes. What weather do you like?
Sun, hot, weather.
Yes. Sunny weather's nice.
Thank you, Selma.
Now, part two.
I'm going to read some situations. I want you to start or answer.
First situation. We're in the street. I start.
Excuse me. Where's the bank, please?
Bank.
It. Go. There.
Oh, thank you. Is it open now?
Yes. Open.
Thank you very much.
OK.
Thank you, Selma.
Thank you.
Is it open now? Yes. Open. Thank you very much.
Now, second situation.
I work in a shop.
You want to buy a pair of shoes.
You start.
Erm, er...
I work in a shop.
You want to buy a pair of shoes.
You start.
I want shoes.
You'd like some shoes? What colour would you like?
Erm, black shoes.
Here are some nice black shoes.
Yes, nice.
OK. Thank you, Selma.
Now, part three.
Here's a picture of a hotel.
I have a different picture of a hotel.
Let's ask and answer questions about the two pictures.
I start.
In my picture, there are two people.
How many people are there in your picture?
One people, one man.
Ask me about my picture.
You have brown chair.
I have a chair, but it's white.
There's a bird on the chair.
Where's the bird in your picture?
Erm, no bird. Oh, yes.
Bird in car.
Ask me a question.
What colour your car?
My car's red.
Yes, car red.
It's eight o'clock. It's eight.
Erm, your picture time?
In my picture, it's three o'clock.
Here, there's a tree and there are some flowers under the tree.
What's under your tree?
Under tree?
Are there flowers under your tree?
Erm, football. No, flowers.
OK. Thank you, Selma.
In part four, I'm going to read something.
I'm going to tell you about Angela's best friend.
I'll read it two times.
Listen and take notes on your paper.
I'll then ask you these questions.
My name is Angelo and my best friend is Paolo.
Paolo is 25 years old and he's a waiter at a café.
We don't meet at the weekend because he always works,
but we meet every Monday and we talk a lot.
Paolo is very funny, so I'm never bored with him.
When the weather isn't cold, we go for a walk in the park or we swim.
Now I'll read it again.
My name is Angelo and my best friend is Paolo.
Paolo is 25 years old and he's a waiter at a café.
We don't meet at the weekend because he always works,
but we meet every Monday and we talk a lot.
Paolo is very funny, so I'm never bored with him.
When the weather isn't cold, we go for a walk in the park or we swim.
Now the questions. What is Paolo's job?
What is Paolo's job?
Waiter.
OK. When does Angelo meet Paolo?
Monday.
Where do they go for a walk?
Park.
OK. Thank you, Selma.
Now you're going to talk on your own for half a minute.
Your topic is your best friend.
You now have 30 seconds to write some notes to help you.
You're going to talk about your best friend.
OK, Selma. Please start.
My best friend is Fatma.
That is Fatma.
Very nice woman, very tall woman.
Hair is black and long, happy person.
Always happy.
Thank you.
Now, Selma, what do you do with Fatma?
Do cooking.
OK. And where do you go with your friends?
Go.
Yes. Where do you go with your friends?
Go swimming pool.
Thank you, Selma. That is the end of the exam.